<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Houtland</title><link href="https://sbadillo.github.io/houtland/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://sbadillo.github.io/houtland/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://sbadillo.github.io/houtland/</id><updated>2018-01-28T00:00:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>Project Launch</title><link href="https://sbadillo.github.io/houtland/project-launch.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-01-28T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-01-28T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>sbadillo</name></author><id>tag:sbadillo.github.io,2018-01-28:/houtland/project-launch.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today the 23.01.2018 was the launch of the project in Eindhoven. Feel free to visit the open tag of the Design Academy where the project is exhibited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presentation for the World vodezel tag in de buik van de Economische Zaken.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" class="img-fluid" src="/images/project-launch-1.png"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" class="img-fluid" src="/images/project-launch-2.png"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today the 23.01.2018 was the launch of the project in Eindhoven. Feel free to visit the open tag of the Design Academy where the project is exhibited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presentation for the World vodezel tag in de buik van de Economische Zaken.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" class="img-fluid" src="/images/project-launch-1.png"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" class="img-fluid" src="/images/project-launch-2.png"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Balano culture and future of food in the Netherlands</title><link href="https://sbadillo.github.io/houtland/balano-culture-and-future-of-food-in-the-netherlands.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-01-21T19:32:05+01:00</published><updated>2018-01-21T19:32:05+01:00</updated><author><name>sbadillo</name></author><id>tag:sbadillo.github.io,2018-01-21:/houtland/balano-culture-and-future-of-food-in-the-netherlands.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Balano culture and future of food in the Netherlands&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the future nuts will play a big part in the diet of the Dutch, such as
Hazelnuts, Walnuts and Acorns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acorns are a neglected food for people, livestock, and domestic animals. Acorns
are easy to collect, store, and process. In addition to the nutritious nut and
meal, acorns yield an oil comparable in quality and flavor with olive oil. The
existing acorn market could be greatly expanded and provide new income for rural
people. A serious effort to identify and propagate the best oak acorn cultivars
for these products is long overdue. [6]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acorns have been used as food by Homo sapiens for thousands of years virtually
everywhere oaks are found. The worldwide destruction of the acorn resource by
mismanagement may well have led to the development of annual plant based
agriculture and to civilisation as we know it today. In Europe, Asia, North
Africa, the Mid-East, and North America, acorns were once a staple food. Balanos
is Greek for acorns, and balanoculture was first mentioned in an article by
David Bainbridge to describe cultures who derive significant subsistence from
acorns. [7] Gathering and processing time for acorns is minimal relative to the
labor required to grow annual cereal grains. He argues that the domestication of
goats which prefer to browse oak seedlings, rising populations afforded by
abundant acorns, and the cutting of trees for fuels, led to the demise of the
great oak woodlands of the Middle East and China and the balanocultures they
supported. Immediately following was the emergence of agriculture and the birth
of granoculture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It takes an Oak tree on average 30 years to begin bearing palatable fruit. Thus
by planting an acorn today, one would help enable a renaissance in balanoculture by 2047.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[6] Jane Zhang, Thesies MDes ’17, Havard University Schoo of Design.
[7] David Robert James Bainbridge, Science writer at University of Cambridge.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Balano culture and future of food in the Netherlands&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the future nuts will play a big part in the diet of the Dutch, such as
Hazelnuts, Walnuts and Acorns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acorns are a neglected food for people, livestock, and domestic animals. Acorns
are easy to collect, store, and process. In addition to the nutritious nut and
meal, acorns yield an oil comparable in quality and flavor with olive oil. The
existing acorn market could be greatly expanded and provide new income for rural
people. A serious effort to identify and propagate the best oak acorn cultivars
for these products is long overdue. [6]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acorns have been used as food by Homo sapiens for thousands of years virtually
everywhere oaks are found. The worldwide destruction of the acorn resource by
mismanagement may well have led to the development of annual plant based
agriculture and to civilisation as we know it today. In Europe, Asia, North
Africa, the Mid-East, and North America, acorns were once a staple food. Balanos
is Greek for acorns, and balanoculture was first mentioned in an article by
David Bainbridge to describe cultures who derive significant subsistence from
acorns. [7] Gathering and processing time for acorns is minimal relative to the
labor required to grow annual cereal grains. He argues that the domestication of
goats which prefer to browse oak seedlings, rising populations afforded by
abundant acorns, and the cutting of trees for fuels, led to the demise of the
great oak woodlands of the Middle East and China and the balanocultures they
supported. Immediately following was the emergence of agriculture and the birth
of granoculture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It takes an Oak tree on average 30 years to begin bearing palatable fruit. Thus
by planting an acorn today, one would help enable a renaissance in balanoculture by 2047.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[6] Jane Zhang, Thesies MDes ’17, Havard University Schoo of Design.
[7] David Robert James Bainbridge, Science writer at University of Cambridge.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Benefits of humans for trees and the other way around</title><link href="https://sbadillo.github.io/houtland/benefits-of-humans-for-trees-and-the-other-way-around.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-01-21T19:32:05+01:00</published><updated>2018-01-21T19:32:05+01:00</updated><author><name>sbadillo</name></author><id>tag:sbadillo.github.io,2018-01-21:/houtland/benefits-of-humans-for-trees-and-the-other-way-around.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Benefits of humans for trees and the other way around&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A key point of my thoughts about this project was the exploration of the values
of beings and things and how these values support each other. It is a positive
calculation, enabling us to see benefits in the things surrounding us and making
use of them, but at the same time also discovering our values in this system.
Offering our strength to enhance the systematic balance, adding benefits to
benefits to create an optimistic calculation beneficial for everyone, and
referring tho the idea that each character needs to understand its place in the
system are key conclusions from my process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Humans are good for making space for trees to grow.
Humans arrange things in their surrounding.
Humans can move things to other places.
Humans create seed banks to preserve diversity.
Humans can enable trees to grow in spaces in which they normally don't grow.
Humans can fertilise trees.
Humans can try to enhance the growth of trees.
Humans can maintain trees.
Humans can protect trees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Forest growth supports life on Earth.
Forest maintains quality of water and air.
Trees stabilise the soil.
Forests enable land based plants and animals to live.
Forests create biodiversity.
Trees grow wealth in form of food and medicine, essential for human health.
Trees absorb carbon dioxide and keep global warming regulated.
A walk in the forest relaxes the human mind.
Forests influence climate and balance out extreme temperatures.
They conserve soil and regulate moisture and stream flow.
Trees prevent soil erosion and floods.
Trees supply raw materials. &lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Benefits of humans for trees and the other way around&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A key point of my thoughts about this project was the exploration of the values
of beings and things and how these values support each other. It is a positive
calculation, enabling us to see benefits in the things surrounding us and making
use of them, but at the same time also discovering our values in this system.
Offering our strength to enhance the systematic balance, adding benefits to
benefits to create an optimistic calculation beneficial for everyone, and
referring tho the idea that each character needs to understand its place in the
system are key conclusions from my process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Humans are good for making space for trees to grow.
Humans arrange things in their surrounding.
Humans can move things to other places.
Humans create seed banks to preserve diversity.
Humans can enable trees to grow in spaces in which they normally don't grow.
Humans can fertilise trees.
Humans can try to enhance the growth of trees.
Humans can maintain trees.
Humans can protect trees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Forest growth supports life on Earth.
Forest maintains quality of water and air.
Trees stabilise the soil.
Forests enable land based plants and animals to live.
Forests create biodiversity.
Trees grow wealth in form of food and medicine, essential for human health.
Trees absorb carbon dioxide and keep global warming regulated.
A walk in the forest relaxes the human mind.
Forests influence climate and balance out extreme temperatures.
They conserve soil and regulate moisture and stream flow.
Trees prevent soil erosion and floods.
Trees supply raw materials. &lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Houtland</title><link href="https://sbadillo.github.io/houtland/houtland.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-01-21T19:32:05+01:00</published><updated>2018-01-21T19:32:05+01:00</updated><author><name>sbadillo</name></author><id>tag:sbadillo.github.io,2018-01-21:/houtland/houtland.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Houtland&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Northern Europe used to be covered by forest, but eventually that forest was
cut down for development of civilisations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During my research I stumbled upon the definition of Holland and was
astonished that it derives from the old dutch word for Houtland meaning
woodland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;”The Netherlands," early 14c., from Dutch Holland, probably Old Dutch holt-
lant "wood land," describing the district around Dordrecht, the nucleus of
Holland. Technically, just one province of the Netherlands, but in English its
use extended to the whole nation.” [3]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The region mentioned was where the early Dutch would harvest its timber for
building and boat constructions. Later the development of reclaiming land from the sea led to a boom in agricultural innovation. Available land was used
extensively for farming, leaving no space for forest growthshaping the Dutch
landscape and food culture that we know today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What if the Netherlands was covered with trees?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The proposal is a complete reforestation of the country imagined through an
array of different scenarios: a forest taking over the Dutch landscape, making
the Netherlands the first truly green country on this planet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the moment three forms come to mind: urban, productive and wild forest,
giving space for all participants in this interconnected system. A deep and
mutual relationship synthesises a resilient and diverse landscape. Trees will
even play a part in food production. Acorns, Hazelnuts and Chestnuts could
become a staple in the future diet of the Dutch in the forms of Chestnut
cheese, Acorn bread, or Hazelnut milk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I noticed during my studies and talks with parties in the food chain that the
food chain system, despite being so highly efficient, must transition from a
system based on chemical fertiliser, monoculture and industrialised pig
stables towards a more permanent, soil-supporting system. Furthermore I
observe that every city talked about increasing greenery in densely urban
areas to improve living quality. All over the country we see urban garden
communities popping up where people come together to think about alternative
approaches to produce food and integrate green in our surroundings. The
combination of all these green movements led me to the realisation that we are
in need of living matter around us. Concrete on its own does not seem to
satisfy us. It is even proven by Japanese-Dutch researchers that walks in a
forest are stress reducing and beneficial for our human immune system. This
trend is not only visible in the Netherlands. It is seen in every
industrialised country where living space in cities gets dense. I take these
developments as a base for my proposal to reforest the entire Netherlands. I
believe that introducing this idea can spark a big discussion of what forest
actually is and how we could integrate trees in such a compact living
environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[3] Dictionary.com&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Houtland&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Northern Europe used to be covered by forest, but eventually that forest was
cut down for development of civilisations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During my research I stumbled upon the definition of Holland and was
astonished that it derives from the old dutch word for Houtland meaning
woodland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;”The Netherlands," early 14c., from Dutch Holland, probably Old Dutch holt-
lant "wood land," describing the district around Dordrecht, the nucleus of
Holland. Technically, just one province of the Netherlands, but in English its
use extended to the whole nation.” [3]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The region mentioned was where the early Dutch would harvest its timber for
building and boat constructions. Later the development of reclaiming land from the sea led to a boom in agricultural innovation. Available land was used
extensively for farming, leaving no space for forest growthshaping the Dutch
landscape and food culture that we know today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What if the Netherlands was covered with trees?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The proposal is a complete reforestation of the country imagined through an
array of different scenarios: a forest taking over the Dutch landscape, making
the Netherlands the first truly green country on this planet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the moment three forms come to mind: urban, productive and wild forest,
giving space for all participants in this interconnected system. A deep and
mutual relationship synthesises a resilient and diverse landscape. Trees will
even play a part in food production. Acorns, Hazelnuts and Chestnuts could
become a staple in the future diet of the Dutch in the forms of Chestnut
cheese, Acorn bread, or Hazelnut milk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I noticed during my studies and talks with parties in the food chain that the
food chain system, despite being so highly efficient, must transition from a
system based on chemical fertiliser, monoculture and industrialised pig
stables towards a more permanent, soil-supporting system. Furthermore I
observe that every city talked about increasing greenery in densely urban
areas to improve living quality. All over the country we see urban garden
communities popping up where people come together to think about alternative
approaches to produce food and integrate green in our surroundings. The
combination of all these green movements led me to the realisation that we are
in need of living matter around us. Concrete on its own does not seem to
satisfy us. It is even proven by Japanese-Dutch researchers that walks in a
forest are stress reducing and beneficial for our human immune system. This
trend is not only visible in the Netherlands. It is seen in every
industrialised country where living space in cities gets dense. I take these
developments as a base for my proposal to reforest the entire Netherlands. I
believe that introducing this idea can spark a big discussion of what forest
actually is and how we could integrate trees in such a compact living
environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[3] Dictionary.com&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>On Natural Growth</title><link href="https://sbadillo.github.io/houtland/on-natural-growth.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-01-21T19:32:05+01:00</published><updated>2018-01-21T19:32:05+01:00</updated><author><name>sbadillo</name></author><id>tag:sbadillo.github.io,2018-01-21:/houtland/on-natural-growth.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h2&gt;On Natural Growth&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The transition towards a system based on natural growth must integrate the idea
of an alternative economic system into our existing economy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Much of the economic decay is undoubtedly due to a heedless and shameful
“neglect of trees.” [4]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We separate the elements from nature and convert them into an irreversible
state. That is industrial production. Nature on the other hand works in the
totally opposite way. Natural systems produce by bringing elements together,
atom by atom. All things in nature are composed of the same building blocks
which return to the earth and are continually cycled through the system. Can we
envision a production system which could function by this principle? My answer
to that question is: the forest. A functioning forest is exactly this kind of
system based on natural growth and decay. It produces and consumes at the same
time while it keeps the balance among all factors. I like to call it producing
in harmony, according the philosophy of Vasudhaiva Kutumbakam . A Sanskrit
phrase [5] found in Hindu texts such as the Maha Upanishad, which means "the world
is one family. One might call it esoteric or naturalistic, but I do believe that
the idea of natural production can be very well translated in contemporary
western society. The challenge here is that we need to rethink our current
systems where profit is valued more that continuity and balance.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next question would be how can we use the ideas of natural growth to supply
us humans with products and at the same time enable all other living beings to
thrive for a fulfilled live. This I discovered in the process of this project. I think one possible answer could lie in how we place ourselves in the ecological system of the planet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, humans can see ourselves as the dominant race. We are able to
influence most known production chains and interactions: the problem being that
often this influence hinders the natural course of things. The more challenging
thought is then, how can we redefine our dominant role towards a role as the
enabler of natural systems. We may still see ourselves as the most developed
race on this planet but the primary goals would shift from a human centred
perspective to a system orientated perspective in a more complicated and
holistic way. We will define ourselves as part of the system which has the
ability to help others to grow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[4] E F Schumacher, German economist.
[5] Philosophy of Vasudhaiva Kutumbakam.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;On Natural Growth&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The transition towards a system based on natural growth must integrate the idea
of an alternative economic system into our existing economy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Much of the economic decay is undoubtedly due to a heedless and shameful
“neglect of trees.” [4]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We separate the elements from nature and convert them into an irreversible
state. That is industrial production. Nature on the other hand works in the
totally opposite way. Natural systems produce by bringing elements together,
atom by atom. All things in nature are composed of the same building blocks
which return to the earth and are continually cycled through the system. Can we
envision a production system which could function by this principle? My answer
to that question is: the forest. A functioning forest is exactly this kind of
system based on natural growth and decay. It produces and consumes at the same
time while it keeps the balance among all factors. I like to call it producing
in harmony, according the philosophy of Vasudhaiva Kutumbakam . A Sanskrit
phrase [5] found in Hindu texts such as the Maha Upanishad, which means "the world
is one family. One might call it esoteric or naturalistic, but I do believe that
the idea of natural production can be very well translated in contemporary
western society. The challenge here is that we need to rethink our current
systems where profit is valued more that continuity and balance.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next question would be how can we use the ideas of natural growth to supply
us humans with products and at the same time enable all other living beings to
thrive for a fulfilled live. This I discovered in the process of this project. I think one possible answer could lie in how we place ourselves in the ecological system of the planet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, humans can see ourselves as the dominant race. We are able to
influence most known production chains and interactions: the problem being that
often this influence hinders the natural course of things. The more challenging
thought is then, how can we redefine our dominant role towards a role as the
enabler of natural systems. We may still see ourselves as the most developed
race on this planet but the primary goals would shift from a human centred
perspective to a system orientated perspective in a more complicated and
holistic way. We will define ourselves as part of the system which has the
ability to help others to grow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[4] E F Schumacher, German economist.
[5] Philosophy of Vasudhaiva Kutumbakam.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>PLAN</title><link href="https://sbadillo.github.io/houtland/plan.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-01-21T19:32:05+01:00</published><updated>2018-01-21T19:32:05+01:00</updated><author><name>sbadillo</name></author><id>tag:sbadillo.github.io,2018-01-21:/houtland/plan.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;!-- this is a comment --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Plan is to start a movement of tree planters all over the country. Each planted tree is part of the Houtland forest and will contribute to a green and diverse country. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alongside we will continue exploring the possibilities of trees and start projects to enhance tree growth in the Netherlands.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;!-- this is a comment --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Plan is to start a movement of tree planters all over the country. Each planted tree is part of the Houtland forest and will contribute to a green and diverse country. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alongside we will continue exploring the possibilities of trees and start projects to enhance tree growth in the Netherlands.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Productive Forest</title><link href="https://sbadillo.github.io/houtland/productive-forest.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-01-21T19:32:05+01:00</published><updated>2018-01-21T19:32:05+01:00</updated><author><name>sbadillo</name></author><id>tag:sbadillo.github.io,2018-01-21:/houtland/productive-forest.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Productive Forest&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To introduce forest in a large scale in the Netherlands we need to develop a
highly productive and super sustainable alternative agricultural system based
on the use of trees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore I propose an alternative system to the contemporary Dutch farming
culture. Introducing a system in which human, plants and animals support,
rather then exploit each other. Inspired by the concept of permaculture and
the ideas of a permanent agriculture by Joseph Russell Smith, we investigate
in how to use native trees to produce a large amount of our food. These trees
are so called crop trees, like the oak, the hazelnut and the chestnut. This
trees are native in the Netherlands and therefore grow naturally in our woods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agroforestry is the practice of planting trees in lines on crop fields. This
has several benefits such as the protection from erosion. Depending on the
trees planted, the farmer also has access to new resources such as fruit,
timber – which can supplement their income while other crops are growing, or
even be used to directly generate energy for the farm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A concern is that the trees’ roots will compete with those of the crops for
valuable resources. But studies have shown that tree roots actually pull their
energy from much deeper in the ground, meaning there’s little overlap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Productive forest will cover a large portion of the Dutch landscape. In fact,
agroforestry looks like a pretty good technique for Dutch farmers, just as it
has proven to be for many others. Organised in a cell structure, this new
system can produce a large amount of human and animal food. The productive
forest functions in multi -layered systems where biodiversity enables strong
and resilient structures which need less human intervention and allow for
bigger yields. With this system we propagate a symbiotic relationship between
humans plants and animals.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Productive Forest&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To introduce forest in a large scale in the Netherlands we need to develop a
highly productive and super sustainable alternative agricultural system based
on the use of trees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore I propose an alternative system to the contemporary Dutch farming
culture. Introducing a system in which human, plants and animals support,
rather then exploit each other. Inspired by the concept of permaculture and
the ideas of a permanent agriculture by Joseph Russell Smith, we investigate
in how to use native trees to produce a large amount of our food. These trees
are so called crop trees, like the oak, the hazelnut and the chestnut. This
trees are native in the Netherlands and therefore grow naturally in our woods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agroforestry is the practice of planting trees in lines on crop fields. This
has several benefits such as the protection from erosion. Depending on the
trees planted, the farmer also has access to new resources such as fruit,
timber – which can supplement their income while other crops are growing, or
even be used to directly generate energy for the farm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A concern is that the trees’ roots will compete with those of the crops for
valuable resources. But studies have shown that tree roots actually pull their
energy from much deeper in the ground, meaning there’s little overlap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Productive forest will cover a large portion of the Dutch landscape. In fact,
agroforestry looks like a pretty good technique for Dutch farmers, just as it
has proven to be for many others. Organised in a cell structure, this new
system can produce a large amount of human and animal food. The productive
forest functions in multi -layered systems where biodiversity enables strong
and resilient structures which need less human intervention and allow for
bigger yields. With this system we propagate a symbiotic relationship between
humans plants and animals.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Reforesting</title><link href="https://sbadillo.github.io/houtland/reforesting.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-01-21T19:32:05+01:00</published><updated>2018-01-21T19:32:05+01:00</updated><author><name>sbadillo</name></author><id>tag:sbadillo.github.io,2018-01-21:/houtland/reforesting.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Reforesting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A forest for me is a place so dense with trees that you cannot just walk into it. It doesn’t matter how big or small they are. “Real” forests are an oasis of wilderness where nature can thrive without human interference. Once upon a time, before human intervention, most of the world we live in today was forest. Then we built up our cities on these forests, forgetting that we belong to nature as well as 8.4 billion other species on this planet. [1]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need to redefine our interactions with our surroundings towards a more sustainable and permanent cooperation of all living beings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s start with trees. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, I propose to completely reforest the Netherlands by the year 2060. Forests cover a third of all land on Earth, providing vital organic infrastructure for some of the planet's densest, most diverse collections of life. Functioning forest systems could be described as the largest living organisms on this planet. A factory of life, where countless biological processes create the most the base resource required for us humans to thrive: fertile soil.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Man lives by plants. Plants live in the soil. The forest is a kind of factory in which the life-force of plants is made by using plant biomaterial, assisted by bacteria and the elements of weather. This important resource is only effectively created by forests all over the world. And we as humans don’t even have to work for it. We just have to let forest grow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently we can observe a new awareness for trees. Dutch cities try to re-green concrete jungles and even the Dutch Institution for forest and nature developed an action plan to increase the tree coverage of the Netherlands. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet these efforts are not enough. Currently, the surface area of the Netherlands is only 11% covered with trees and is one of Europe's least wooded countries. On the other hand, the Netherlands is extremely productive relative to its size as a food exporter. Therefore the Netherlands rely deeply on its high quality soil and innovation in the agricultural sector. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of exciting new technologies are changing how we view agriculture; such as farming in silos, drone farmers, self-driving tractors and vertical farming, but I believe not every innovation has to be so flashy and futuristic. The latest trend of reshaping rural environments is pretty down to Earth. This trend is agroforestry, the art of planting trees. [2]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1] Shubhendu Sharma, CEO of Afforestt. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[2] The Guedian, The latest cutting-edge technology changing our landscapes? Trees.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Reforesting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A forest for me is a place so dense with trees that you cannot just walk into it. It doesn’t matter how big or small they are. “Real” forests are an oasis of wilderness where nature can thrive without human interference. Once upon a time, before human intervention, most of the world we live in today was forest. Then we built up our cities on these forests, forgetting that we belong to nature as well as 8.4 billion other species on this planet. [1]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need to redefine our interactions with our surroundings towards a more sustainable and permanent cooperation of all living beings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s start with trees. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, I propose to completely reforest the Netherlands by the year 2060. Forests cover a third of all land on Earth, providing vital organic infrastructure for some of the planet's densest, most diverse collections of life. Functioning forest systems could be described as the largest living organisms on this planet. A factory of life, where countless biological processes create the most the base resource required for us humans to thrive: fertile soil.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Man lives by plants. Plants live in the soil. The forest is a kind of factory in which the life-force of plants is made by using plant biomaterial, assisted by bacteria and the elements of weather. This important resource is only effectively created by forests all over the world. And we as humans don’t even have to work for it. We just have to let forest grow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently we can observe a new awareness for trees. Dutch cities try to re-green concrete jungles and even the Dutch Institution for forest and nature developed an action plan to increase the tree coverage of the Netherlands. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet these efforts are not enough. Currently, the surface area of the Netherlands is only 11% covered with trees and is one of Europe's least wooded countries. On the other hand, the Netherlands is extremely productive relative to its size as a food exporter. Therefore the Netherlands rely deeply on its high quality soil and innovation in the agricultural sector. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of exciting new technologies are changing how we view agriculture; such as farming in silos, drone farmers, self-driving tractors and vertical farming, but I believe not every innovation has to be so flashy and futuristic. The latest trend of reshaping rural environments is pretty down to Earth. This trend is agroforestry, the art of planting trees. [2]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1] Shubhendu Sharma, CEO of Afforestt. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[2] The Guedian, The latest cutting-edge technology changing our landscapes? Trees.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>The Tree Crop Exploration</title><link href="https://sbadillo.github.io/houtland/the-tree-crop-exploration.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-01-21T19:32:05+01:00</published><updated>2018-01-21T19:32:05+01:00</updated><author><name>sbadillo</name></author><id>tag:sbadillo.github.io,2018-01-21:/houtland/the-tree-crop-exploration.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h2&gt;The Tree Crop Exploration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plan is to set up the Tree Crop Exploration: a research platform exploring
the potential of the trees. This plan is categorised in tree main chapters.
First the public campaign to inform and involve people, and to create outreach
to attach potential partners and collaborations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second stage is the experimental research. This combines scientific
approaches and alternative methods to work together expressing tree potential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the goal to set up unconventional applications, such forward thinking
test farms and a global network of collaboration supporting tradition from
conventional agriculture towards holistic tree based systems.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;The Tree Crop Exploration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plan is to set up the Tree Crop Exploration: a research platform exploring
the potential of the trees. This plan is categorised in tree main chapters.
First the public campaign to inform and involve people, and to create outreach
to attach potential partners and collaborations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second stage is the experimental research. This combines scientific
approaches and alternative methods to work together expressing tree potential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the goal to set up unconventional applications, such forward thinking
test farms and a global network of collaboration supporting tradition from
conventional agriculture towards holistic tree based systems.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Urban Forest</title><link href="https://sbadillo.github.io/houtland/urban-forest.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-01-21T19:32:05+01:00</published><updated>2018-01-21T19:32:05+01:00</updated><author><name>sbadillo</name></author><id>tag:sbadillo.github.io,2018-01-21:/houtland/urban-forest.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Urban Forest&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The urban forest aims at the perfect symbiosis between humans and plants. It
will grow in human cities and densely populated areas and will cover all
available space which is not necessarily used by humans. A large part will be
urban recreation areas where people can go and enjoy a walk through the woods.
The forest will be a mix of leaf trees, mainly evergreen, and fruit bearing
trees. It will be a a source of free food for the city dwellers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the harvesting season the community can organise harvesting feasts. The
food should be for free and not capitalised on by any particular individual.
This feast can be used to strengthen the interaction in-between trees and
humans to celebrate a community of trees and plants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The urban forest will also provide health benefits to its human partners.
Humans will enable plants to explore new areas such as rooftops and vertical
walls of buildings and even artificial climate zones inside buildings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Experimental architecture can provide new living areas for trees. Such as
vertical forest towers, where trees can grow alongside the high-rise building
towards the sky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An argument against allowing trees to grow freely in urban areas would be that
the roots of trees would destroy foundations and tubing under the ground.
However, speaking with an architect from Eindhoven who built his house in
consideration of the oak trees on his plot. He showed that there is a very
simple solution for these common objections. Houses next to trees could be
built with a pillar foundation so that the roots can grow underneath the house
without getting damaged or damaging the foundation of the building.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Urban Forest&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The urban forest aims at the perfect symbiosis between humans and plants. It
will grow in human cities and densely populated areas and will cover all
available space which is not necessarily used by humans. A large part will be
urban recreation areas where people can go and enjoy a walk through the woods.
The forest will be a mix of leaf trees, mainly evergreen, and fruit bearing
trees. It will be a a source of free food for the city dwellers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the harvesting season the community can organise harvesting feasts. The
food should be for free and not capitalised on by any particular individual.
This feast can be used to strengthen the interaction in-between trees and
humans to celebrate a community of trees and plants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The urban forest will also provide health benefits to its human partners.
Humans will enable plants to explore new areas such as rooftops and vertical
walls of buildings and even artificial climate zones inside buildings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Experimental architecture can provide new living areas for trees. Such as
vertical forest towers, where trees can grow alongside the high-rise building
towards the sky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An argument against allowing trees to grow freely in urban areas would be that
the roots of trees would destroy foundations and tubing under the ground.
However, speaking with an architect from Eindhoven who built his house in
consideration of the oak trees on his plot. He showed that there is a very
simple solution for these common objections. Houses next to trees could be
built with a pillar foundation so that the roots can grow underneath the house
without getting damaged or damaging the foundation of the building.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Wild forest</title><link href="https://sbadillo.github.io/houtland/wild-forest.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-01-21T19:32:05+01:00</published><updated>2018-01-21T19:32:05+01:00</updated><author><name>sbadillo</name></author><id>tag:sbadillo.github.io,2018-01-21:/houtland/wild-forest.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Wild Forest&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The natural forest is the backbone of the whole system. It is an oasis of
wilderness to allow biodiversity and natural balance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will introduce natural reserves all over the country in which nature can
thrive without human interventions. In these places we can only be present as
observers- to get inspired and learn how natural systems work and thrive.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Wild Forest&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The natural forest is the backbone of the whole system. It is an oasis of
wilderness to allow biodiversity and natural balance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will introduce natural reserves all over the country in which nature can
thrive without human interventions. In these places we can only be present as
observers- to get inspired and learn how natural systems work and thrive.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry></feed>